Can't focus. My body is still puzzled about what to do.
集中できてないな　まだ体が迷っているんだ
Shuuchuu dekitenaina mada karada ga mayotteirunda
I'm trembling. I can't stop even if I try to control myself.
震えていたんじゃ　コントロールしたってブレるんだ
Furueteitanja kontoroorushitatte burerunda
Although neither sun nor moon are on my side,
ツキ
太陽も勝負運もなんも完全にこっち向いていないが
Taiyou mo tsuki mo nanmo kanzen ni kocchi muiteinaiga
"I've no choice but to try,"
「やるしかないんだ」
Yarushikanainda
Those were the words I muttered to myself.
言い聞かせるようにそうつぶやいた
Iikikaseruyouni sotto tsubuyaita
The odds aren't on my side, but running way'd be gutless.
状況は悪いが　ただ逃げ出すんじゃ根性ないなぁ
Joukyou wa waruiga tada nigedasunja konjou nainaa
Even if I can't see the future, I'll just have to win it over with courage.
展望はないが　度胸でクリアするしかないや
Tenbou wa naiga dokyou de kuria suru shika naiya
Need to keep distance from the target as I hold myself back.
衝動は抑えたままターゲットとの間隔探れ
Shoudou wa osaetamama taagetto to no kankaku sagure
All that's needed for victory is pride to win.
必要なもんは勝つプライド
Hitsuyou na mon wa katsu puraido
Will we celebrate with the wine of victory
味わうのは勝利の美酒か
Ajiwau nowa shouri no bishu ka
Or'll we end up kissing their feet in defeat?
それとも敗北の苦汁か
Soretomo haiboku no kujuu ka
There are two outcomes to everything.
そう　すべては2つに1つ
Sou subete wa futatsu ni hitotsu
I want to control destiny.
操りたい運命の糸
Ayatsuritai unmei no ito
I need to seize the golden opportunity with my hands.
絶好のゴールデンタイム　この手で掴め
Zekkou no goorudentaimu kono te de tsukame
I'll finish it up with my best poker face,
渾身のポーカーフェイス　キメて仕掛けるよ
Konshin no pookaafeisu kimete shikakeruyo
And drag them into a world of illusions.
イリュージョンの世界へ引きずり込んで
Iryuujon no sekai e hikizurikonde
I'll find my way out of this endless pressure game,
際限無いプレッシャーゲーム　スルリと抜けて
Saigennai puresshaageemu sururito nukete
And leap over the borderline of honor.
栄光のボーダーライン　飛び越えるために
Eikou no boodaarain tobikoeru tameni
How many? What'll I need to sacrifice to make it happen?
ハウメニー？　どれくらいの代償がいる？
Haumenii? Dorekurai no daishou ga iru?
What is the one thing I don't want to let go?
手放したくないもんはどれ？
Tebanashitakunai mon wa dore?
確かに…
Well...
これそっくりだけど…
It really does look like the drawing, but...
うちの子かわいいでしょ
Isn't she just the cutest thing?
絶対違う
That's definitely not it!
分かってるよ
I know that!
っていうかオレたちこんな細かいギャグに
We really don't have time for these jokes!
つきあってる暇ねぇんだよ
ほんと…
Really...
どこにいるんだろう…
Where could she be?
イーストシティイーストシティ
East City!
You've arrived in East City!
スカーの新しい情報だ
Here's the latest news on Scar.
まだ逃げてるのかあいつ
He's still on the run?
しぶといヤツだな
What a persistent guy.
Oh my, I'm terribly sorry.
あらあらごめんなさいねぇ
いえよそ見しててすみません
No, it's my fault for not paying attention.
珍しい衣装ね外国の方
You are wearing some unusual attire.
Are you not from this country?
シンから来ました
I'm from Xing.
あらまあ観光かしら
Oh, my.
Are you here to see the sights?
イーストシティって見る所ないでしょ
There's not much to see in East City, is there?
いえ乗り継ぎで寄っただけで
No, I just stopped by because I need to switch trains here.
これから北へ行くんです
I'm headed to the North.
３番ホームから出発の…
The train at Platform No. 3 is headed for North City.
いけない
Oh, no!
おばあさんありがとう
Thank you for helping me pick up the groceries!
If you are planning on riding with us, please board at once.
気をつけてね
Have a safe trip!
Hm?
変わった猫ちゃんねぇ
What a peculiar kitty.
どこへ行った
Where did he go?!
確かに足音は聞こえたのですが…
I know I heard footsteps...
There he is!
あそこだ
黒髪の中年男と一緒にいたのですね
So he was with a middle-aged man with black hair?
Yes. According to the reports, sir.
はいそう報告を受けています
ここが昨日
This is where he was yesterday.
西ですか
So he's headed West, huh?
こちらは
We have a few injured, some slightly, others seriously.
重軽傷者数名を出しました
スカーも必死なのでしょう
Scar must be desperate, too.
それにしても…
But even so...
目立ちすぎですね
...he's attracting a lot of attention.
さて仕事に出かけましょう
Now, let's head off to work.
Well, whatever.
まあいいでしょう
That has nothing to do with me.
私には関係ない
お葬式ですのね
A funeral, eh?
はあそのようですが
Yes, it seems so.
嫌なものよね
It isn't pretty, is it?
この歳になると
When you get old like me, you can't help but think about when you'll be the one getting buried.
いつ自分がああなるのかばかり
考えてしまう
何をおっしゃいますかご婦人
What a terrible thing to say, madam.
見たところまだお若い
As far as I can see, you have a long life ahead of you.
グラマン中将閣下
Lieutenant General Grumman?!
待ち合わせはヒューズ准将の
You said we were going to meet in front of Brigadier General Hughes' grave, right?
お墓の前でしたわよねぇ
最終手段を使ったということは
I figured it was something serious since you decided to take the measure of last resort.
ただごとではないと思ってね
念には念を入れ
To be doubly sure, I decided to disguise myself.
変装してきたのよね
いやさすが変人と名高いグラマン閣下
Well, I shouldn't have expected less from you, a man so famous for his eccentricity.
予想外の変装です
Your disguise exceeded my expectations.
変人
Eccentric?
褒め言葉として受け取っておきましょ
I'll take that as a compliment.
でなんの用
So, what's the matter?
錬丹術
Eastern Alchemy.
中央図書館でなら
We may be able to find something in the Central Library.
何か分かるかもね
Maybe.
Since we can't find the midget,
we'll have to search on our own.
豆粒女が見つからない以上
自分たちで調べるしかない
少しでも手がかり見つかるといいね
I hope we can at least find some clues.
なるほどセントラル上層部はすべて黒か
I see. So the entire upper echelon of Central is guilty, huh?
しかし情報と引き換えに
But you lost far too much in exchange for the information.
失ったもの多すぎ
信用できる部下を引きはがされちゃったら
You have nothing left if they take away the men you can trust.
元も子もないでしょ
You're right, sir. I can't argue with that.
返す言葉もありません
はぁレイブンまでもか…
Even Raven, huh...
少し昔わしが
When I was in Central a little while ago, Raven asked me...
セントラルにいたころにね
レイブンに聞かれたよ
「完全なる不死の軍団に興味はないか」とな
"Are you interested in a perfect, immortal army?"
不死の軍団
Immortal army?
人造人間のことか
Was he talking about the Homunculi?
「不死などくだらん」と
I flat-out rejected him, saying that it was rubbish.
一蹴してやった
そしたらその後すぐわし
Then soon after,
東方司令部に飛ばされちゃった
I was sent to Eastern Headquarters.
左遷ですか
Relegated?
お陰でゴタゴタとうるさい
Thanks to that, I'm now stuck cleaning up after all the messes in the East.
東部問題の尻ぬぐいを
し続けるはめになったよ
ゴタゴタといえば
More on that topic, do you happen to remember the riot in Lior?
リオールの暴動を覚えておいでですか
レト教のえせ教主の陰謀が
The case where the Fullmetal Alchemist exposed the fake priest of Leto's conspiracy.
鋼の錬金術師によって暴かれた事件です
Yes, I do remember.
覚えとるよ
リオールは大混乱に陥りましたが
Although Lior was thrown into disarray,
初期の段階で東方軍が迅速に行動して
the riot was quickly suppressed thanks to the
Eastern Army's rapid response while it was still minor.
暴動を抑えることができました
がセントラル軍が出張ってきて
But the Central Army intruded on the scene, and the Eastern Army was withdrawn.
東方軍はお払い箱にされた…
だったっけな
Am I right?
Yes.
リオールの治安が急激に悪化したのは
Lior's public order suddenly turned for
the worse when the Central Army entered the scene.
セントラル軍が入ってきてからです
セントラルのヤツら
Those guys at Central are really
planning something, aren't they?
なんか企んでるよねぇ
I don't even want to think about it!
やだやだわしの引退まで
平穏無事でいてくれんもんかのう
Can't things be peaceful until I retire?
またまたご冗談を
Again with the jokes.
グラマン閣下ともあろうお方が
You're the great Lieutenant General Grumman.
地方の長で満足する気など
I'm sure you haven't felt satisfied for a second at simply being the head man for a region of the country.
かけらもないのでしょう
イシュヴァールを経験した屈強な兵を擁する
You have the Eastern Army on your side;
full of veteran soldiers who experienced Ishbal.
東方軍を持っておられるというのに
極秘連絡用メモを使うのは
I had always thought you'd use that secret contact memo when you needed to whine and beg me for help.
わしに泣きつくときだと思っていたが
わしをたきつけるためにここに呼んだか
But you called me here to get me worked up, huh?
やれやれ…
Geez...
セントラルが面白いことになってきたお陰で
Now that things are getting interesting in Central,
消えかかっていた野望の火種が
the flame of ambition in my heart has been lit once more.
また燃え上がってきたわい
本気を出すと化粧が崩れますよご婦人
Don't get too serious or your makeup will be ruined, madam.
Oh, no!
あら　いけない
この後お暇ですか
Are you free after this?
If you don't mind, would you like to join me for a cup of tea?
よろしければどこかでお茶でも
まあごめんなさいね
Oh, no, thank you.
お誘いはうれしいけど…
I appreciate the invitation, but...
ダメだ
It's no good.
なんでこんなに
Why doesn't this place have any good books on Eastern Alchemy?
錬丹術の記述が少ねぇんだよ
Maybe I'll just visit Xing and study there instead...
いっそシンに渡って
本場物を学ぶか…
いやしかし
Wait, but there's no way I'll be able to cross that desert with my automail...
機械鎧であの砂漠越えは…
見つけたぞ
There you are, Edward Elric.
エドワード·エルリック
しょ…少佐 何やってんだ
M-Major! What are you doing here?!
Shh!
図書館ではお静かに…である
You have to be quiet in the library.
お主白黒猫を連れた
I heard you're after a girl from Xing
who carries around a black and white cat.
シンの少女を追っておるらしいな
Yeah.
ってなんで知ってるんだよ
Wait, how did you know that?
マスタング大佐に聞いた
I heard from Colonel Mustang.
今日我が輩は大佐の使いだ
I'm here today on the Colonel's orders.
その少女北へ向かうらしいぞ
Apparently, she's headed north.
目撃者の話によると
According to a witness, she was in
East City and was headed north from there.
イーストシティから
北へ行くと言っていたとか
北か
North, huh?
よしそんだけ分かりゃ動ける
Okay. If we know that much, it's safe to give it a try.
少佐ありがとな
Thanks a lot, Major.
大佐にも礼言っといて
Tell the Colonel I said thanks, too.
Hang on.
待て待て焦るな
Don't be in such a rush.
持っていけ
Take this with you.
なんだこれ
What's this?
紹介状だ
It's a letter of introduction.
役に立たんかもしれんが
It may not do you much good,
まず会え
but you should meet her first.
会えって誰に
Meet who?
北方司令部より更に北
She resides even farther north than the Northern Headquarters.
ドラクマとの国境を守り
A general who guards the Drakma border and holds another name, the "Northern Wall of Briggs"...
「ブリッグズの北壁」の異名を持つ将軍…
アームストロング少将だ
...Major General Armstrong.
急げ
Hurry!
You've got nowhere to run, Scar!
スカーもう逃げられんぞ
どこへ
Where did he go?!
司令部に報告しろ
Report this to Headquarters!
あれはウエストシティ行きの列車だ
That train is headed for West City!
くそ
Damn him...
これといった錬丹術の記述は
I can't really find much on Eastern Alchemy...
見つからないなぁ
あのメイって子の遠隔錬成術
May's long-distance transmutation was awesome.
すごかったな
あれ使えたらいいなぁ
I wish I could use that...
ノックス先生のところにいるときに
I should have asked her about it when she was still at Dr. Nox's place.
もっと聞いておけばよかった
リンは医学に特化した技術って
Ling said that it's used predominantly for medical purposes...
言ってたけど…
鋼の錬金術師さんの兄弟の
Are you the Fullmetal Alchemist's little brother who wears a giant suit wherever he goes?
大きい鎧さんですか
そっそうだけど…
Y-Yes...
すごい
Amazing!
Wow! Wow!
Thanks...
どうも…っていうか図書館ではお静かに
But you need to keep it down. We're in a library.
Oh, I'm sorry.
すみません
なんの勉強してるんですか
What are you studying?
錬丹術だよ
Eastern Alchemy.
れんたん術
Eastern Alchemy?
It's a form of alchemy used in Xing.
シンの国の錬金術
へえシンの国の…
Wow... Xing, huh?
でもエルリック兄弟は
But aren't you Elric Brothers skilled enough to be state qualified in Amestris, a nation so advanced in alchemy?
この錬金術先進国のアメストリスで
国家資格を取れるほどの
腕利きなんでしょ
それがなんで他国のマイナーな錬金術を
Why are you researching minor forms of alchemy used in other countries?
調べてるんですか
Huh?
僕の体を取り戻すとか
I can't exactly say, "I'm looking for a way to get my body back and fight Homunculi"...
人造人間に対抗する方法を探ってる…
なんて言えないよな
えっと…
Umm...
錬丹術は医学方面に
They say that Eastern Alchemy is used predominantly for medical purposes.
特化してるというからね
人の命を救う技術として
I'm researching to see if there are any other ways human lives could be saved.
新たな可能性がないか研究してるのさ
Wow! Nothing less to be expected from the Elric Brothers!
さすが噂のエルリック兄弟だ
アルアルフォンス
Al! Alphonse!
支度しろ行くぞ
Get your things together! We're leaving!
兄さん図書館ではお静かに…
Brother, you have to keep it down in the library!
ってどこ行くって
Wait, where are we going?
詳しい話は歩きながら説明する
I'll explain the details on the way.
とにかく出発だ
Either way, we need to go.
ホテルの荷物をまとめろ
Go to the hotel and pack.
どこのガキだ
Whose brat is this?
鎧さんのお兄さんってことは
If you're his brother, it must mean you're Edward, the State Alchemist!
国家錬金術師のエドワードさん
Yeah.
Wow!
噂どおりちっちゃい錬金術師だ
So the rumors were true! You really are a tiny alchemist!
カチン
What?!
おま…お前
H-Hey...
もう一回言ってみろ…
Say that again...
もっかい言ってみろ
Come on, say it again.
飛ぶよ海王星辺りいっとく
You're up for a ride.
Want me to blast you to Neptune?
Wow!
噂どおり小さいって言ったら
So they were right! You get really angry when people say you're short!
ぶちキレるんだ
セリム様から離れろ
Back away from Sir Selim!
撃っちゃダメですよ
You can't shoot him!
もしかしてセリム·ブラッドレイ
Don't tell me... you're Selim Bradley?
大総統の息子の
The Führer President's son?!
はいそうです
Yup! That's right!
なんでこうなるんだ
What the heck are we doing here?
オレたち北に行くはずだろ
Aren't we supposed to be headed north?
そんなこと言われても…
Not like it was my choice...
ごめんなさいね
I'm sorry.
この子ずっとエドワードさんにあこがれてて
This boy has admired you for so long, Mr. Edward.
あこがれ
Admired?
セリム君は錬金術が好きなの
Do you like alchemy, Selim?
はい僕も錬金術を習って
I do.
My dream is to learn alchemy and become a State Alchemist like Mr. Edward.
エドワードさんみたいな
国家錬金術師になるのが夢です
オレにあこがれて…
Admired me, huh...
Wow...
そして
Then, I want to be useful to Father.
お義父さんの役に立ちたいんです
お義父さんは…
Do you love your Father...
キング·ブラッドレイ大総統は
...Führer President King Bradley?
好きか
もちろんです
Of course!
お義父さんってどんな人かな
What's he like?
立派な人です普通の人なら
He's a very noble man.
He perseveres through hard work that would make a normal person cry...
音を上げてしまうような激務にも耐え
毎日国民のことだけを考えて
...and works every day with only one thing in mind: the well-being of his people.
行動しています
そうなんだ
I see.
大総統は毎日忙しそうだものね
The Führer President does  seem busy all the time.
Yes, he is.
そうなのよ
あの人まだ現役で
He still plans on working to his fullest in active service.
バリバリ働くつもりなの
もういい歳なんだから休めばいいのに
I'm constantly telling him to retire already, bearing his age in mind.
昔っから仕事一辺倒の人でね
He's always been someone totally committed to his work.
仕事はできるけど
He can do his job, but he's always been a blockhead when it comes to women.
女心の分からない
唐変木だったわ
もう失礼な男で
He was so impolite; I gave him a good slap across the face.
私ビンタ張ってしまったの
まあそれが縁で
Well, that's where it all started. Then, we started dating.
おつきあいを始めて
最初のデートがこれまた…
And our first date was...
ってあらいけない
Oh, my.
のろけ話になってしまったわね
I didn't mean to talk about senseless things.
お義父さん
Father!
まあ
What a surprise!
お帰りなさい
Welcome home!
Thanks, Selim.
セリム
どうしたんですの
Why the surprise visit?
珍しく時間が空いたので
I had some rare free time, so I came to see your faces.
お前たちの顔を見にな
すると鋼の錬金術師君が
Then, I heard the Fullmetal Alchemist was here.
来ていると聞いてね
どうも
Hello.
お久しぶりです
It's been a while.
中央司令部で会ったばかりじゃないか
We just saw each other at Central Headquarters, didn't we?
そうか図書館で出会ったのか
I see. So you met each other at the library.
はい
Yep!
似てないと言いたいのかね
What, are you trying to say that we don't look alike?
いっいえそういうわけじゃあ…
N-No, that's not it...
この子と血のつながりはない
We're not connected by blood.
私たち夫婦に子供ができなかったの
We were never able to have kids.
だから親せきの子を養子にもらったのよ
So we adopted him from a relative.
親思いで優しい子に育ってくれた
He grew up to become a kind boy who cares so much for his parents.
やめてよお義父さん
Stop it, Father.
恥ずかしいです
It's embarrassing.
本当のことだろう
I'm only stating the truth.
何かね
Is something the matter?
いっいえ…いつも司令部にいらっしゃる姿しか
N-No, it's just that we only see you when you're working at Headquarters.
見ていないので
やっぱりほらねえ…
So it's just... right, Brother?
イ…イメージのギャップってやつですよ
I guess we're just stunned to see such a different side of you.
そうか私にも家族がいるんだよ
I see.
I, too, have family.
こんな私にもね
Even someone like me.
君たちの家族とは少し違うが
Although it's a bit different from your family.
お義父さんもう行っちゃうんですか
Are you leaving already, Father?
Yeah. It's about time for me to return to the office.
そろそろ公務に戻る時間だ
ゆっくりしていってくれたまえ
Enjoy your stay,
国家錬金術師君
State Alchemist.
行くぞ
Let's go.
また遊びに来てくださいね
Come visit again!
Okay, thanks.
またな
奥さんも息子さんも
I don't think his wife or son know that he's a Homunculus...
大総統が人造人間だってこと…
Anyway, we need to head north! All the way!
とにかく北だ北へ行くぞ
豆粒女とっつかまえて
We need to get a hold of that midget and
make her tell us the secret behind Eastern Alchemy!
錬丹術の秘密聞き出してやる
Right!
朝には着く眠っておけ
We'll be there by morning.
Sleep for now.
I see... so you let them get away again.
そう…
まんまと逃げおおせましたか
これはウエストエリアの地図ですね
This is a map of the West, correct?
Yes, sir.
はい
最後に目撃されたのはここ
He was last seen...
Here.
ウエストシティはここ
And this is West City.
この間のどこかで
Scar and Marcoh disappeared somewhere in between.
スカーとマルコーは消えた
カーブでは速度をかなり落としますね
A train must slow down significantly at a curve, correct?
飛び降りることは可能ですか
Is it possible for someone to jump off?
できなくはないでしょうが
I wouldn't say it's impossible, but it's very dangerous.
とても危険です
そうですか
I see.
さて飛び降りて
Well then, I wonder which direction they ran after they jumped off?
どっちへ逃げたんでしょうね
北か南か…
North...
...or south...
Even if we part and meet again, I want to meet at this place.
巡り巡ってもまたここで逢いたい
Megurimeguttemo mata koko de aitai
Then we'll hold hands to ensure we'll never be separated again.
はぐれないようにこの手をつなぐんだ
Hagurenaiyouni kono te wo tsunagunda
We used to talk all night until the sun rose,
朝日が昇るまで語り合ったね
Asahi ga noboru made katariattane
And held hands till the sun went under the horizon.
夕陽が沈むまでつないだ手
Yuuhi ga shizumu made tsunaida te
Let's walk together like this forever, like light and shadow.
こうやって明日も明後日も共に歩もう光と影
Kouyatte asu mo asatte mo tomo ni ayumou hikari to kage
I stand in the city, staring off into space with lonely eyes.
寂しげに見つめる街の中で
Samishige ni mitsumeru machi no naka de
I can't find warmth on my own.
温もりはひとりじゃ見つからなくて
Nukumori wa hitori ja mitsukaranakute
By meeting you, I realized
愛がこんなに強さになること
Ai ga konnani tsuyosa ni narukoto
How much strength love could give me.
知ったんだ　キミに出逢えてはじめて
Shittanda kimi ni deaete hajimete
Even if we part and meet again, I want to meet at this place.
巡り巡ってもまたここで逢いたい
Megurimeguttemo mata koko de aitai
Then we'll hold hands to ensure we'll never be separated again.
はぐれないようにこの手をつなぐんだ
Hagurenaiyouni kono te wo tsunagunda
I can't sleep by myself, 'cause I can't dream without you.
一人じゃ眠れない　夢は見れないから
Hitori ja nemurenai yume wa mirenaikara
So take me to a place where uncertainty can't reach us
どんな不安も届かないところへ
Donna fuan mo todokanai tokoro e
And let us bring light to the night sky with no stars.
星のない夜も照らし続けよう
Hoshi no yoru mo terashitsuzukeyou
So long as you're with me, I can go to world's end.
何処までも行けるキミとなら
Doko made mo yukeru kimi to nara
Even if it's a path I can't walk on my own,
一人じゃ歩けない道も二人なら
Hitori ja arukenai michi mo futari nara
If you're by my side, I can walk it while humming a tune.
鼻歌歌いながら歩けるんだ
Hanauta utainagara arukerunda
If we're together, the world is mine.
キミがいれば幸せ
Kimi ga ireba shiawase
北に行くのって
Could it be our first time traveling north?
もしかしたら初めてじゃない
そうだな
Yeah.
雪見られるかな
I wonder if we'll be able to see snow?
雪か…
Snow, huh...
リゼンブールじゃ
I guess it rarely stuck to the ground in Resembool.
めったに積もらなかったからな
追う者追われる者
日本語字幕仕上げ：XIAOBIN
The cat and the mouse.
白い世界でぶつかり合う
Insanity and hatred clash in a white world.
狂気と憎しみ
漫遊字幕組
http://popgo.net/bbs
かつてない激闘は
The fiercest battle yet opens the gate to a new world.
新たなる世界への扉を開く
次回　鋼の錬金術師
Next time, Fullmetal Alchemist:
Fullmetal　Alchemist
第３３話　「ブリッグズの北壁」
Episode 33, The Northern Wall of Briggs.
金色の髪 それは 氷で出来た炎
Her golden hair is a flame made of ice.